{"name": "54D 1999", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. If 2x - 3 = 12, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "2.0", "B": "4.5", "C": "7.5", "D": "9.0", "E": "15.0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Consider the following two logical statements.\n    If the length of AB is 2, then the length of BC is 5.     The length of BC is NOT 5.\nIf these statements are both true, then it follows that the length of:", "choices": {"A": "AB is NOT 2.", "B": "AB is 2.", "C": "AB is 5.", "D": "BC is 2.", "E": "BC is NOT 2."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. If the probability that it will rain tomorrow is 0.7, what is the probability that it will NOT rain tomorrow?", "choices": {"A": "0.0", "B": "0.1", "C": "0.3", "D": "1.0", "E": "1.7"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. Mario bought 1 compact disc for $8.95 and 3 others for $7.99 each. What was the average price per disc he paid for these 4 compact discs?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. On Saturday Sid received his pay and spent of it.  On Sunday he spent  of the remaining money, and on Monday he spent  of what remained from Sunday. If $4 then remained, how much pay did he receive originally?", "choices": {"A": "$12", "B": "$16", "C": "$24", "D": "$32", "E": "$64"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. If N = -3a and M = 2b - a, then what is the value of N + M?", "choices": {"A": "-4a + 2b", "B": "-4a - 2b", "C": "-3a + 2b", "D": "-2a + 2b", "E": "-2a - 2b"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. In the figure below, l1 is parallel to l2, l3 is parallel to l4, and the lines intersect as shown. What is the measure of angle z ?", "choices": {"A": "110\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "130\u00b0", "D": "140\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. If x = -4, then -x2 - 5x + 3 = ?", "choices": {"A": "31", "B": "15", "C": "7", "D": "-25", "E": "-33"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. The average of 6 numbers is 4.5. If each of the numbers is decreased by 4, what is the average of the 6 new numbers?", "choices": {"A": "0.0", "B": "0.5", "C": "4.5", "D": "5.0", "E": "9.0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. The expression 7a + 7b is equivalent to which of the following?", "choices": {"A": "7(a + b)", "B": "14(a + b)", "C": "7a + b", "D": "7ab", "E": "14ab"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. For each day on your newspaper route you receive $10.00 plus a fixed amount for each newspaper you deliver. Currently you are earning $18.00 per day for delivery of 80 newspapers. Today you are assigned to deliver 20 additional newspapers per day. What will be your new daily earnings?", "choices": {"A": "$10.00", "B": "$18.20", "C": "$19.00", "D": "$20.00", "E": "$22.50"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. If  \uff0cwhat is the largest possible value for x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "8", "E": "15"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. What is the number of degrees the hour hand of a clock moves in 10 hours ?", "choices": {"A": "100\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "150\u00b0", "D": "220\u00b0", "E": "300\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3POQ and \u25b3SRQ are isosceles right triangles with equal areas. Points O, P, Q, and R are located on the axes as shown. Which of the following could be the coordinates of point S ?", "choices": {"A": "(0, 14)", "B": "(7, 0)", "C": "(7, 14)", "D": "(14, 0)", "E": "(14, 7)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Which of the following equations has both x = 2 and x = -3 as solutions ?", "choices": {"A": " (x - 2)(x + 3) = 0", "B": "(x + 2)(x + 3) = 0", "C": "(x - 2)(-x + 3) = 0", "D": "(x + 2)(x - 3) = 0", "E": "x - 2 = x + 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. A theater has m rows of seats with (n + p) seats in each row. Which of the following is an expression for the number of seats in the entire theater ?", "choices": {"A": "(m \u00b7 n) + p", "B": "(m \u00b7 n) + (m \u00b7 p)", "C": "n + (m \u00b7 n)", "D": "m \u00b7 n \u00b7 p", "E": "m + n + p"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. If 40% of x equals 80, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "32", "C": "200", "D": "2,000", "E": "3,200"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The cost of electricity at the local utility company is 10 cents per kilowatt-hour for the first 100 kilowatt-hours used in a month and 7 cents per kilowatt-hour for each additional kilowatt-hour used. What is the cost for 500 kilowatt-hours used in 1 month?", "choices": {"A": "$28.00", "B": "$35.00", "C": "$38.00", "D": "$50.00", "E": "$85.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. You are standing in line at the cash register to pay for a bracelet priced at $15.99. A sales tax of 8% of the $15.99 will be added (rounded to the nearest cent) to the price of the bracelet. You have 20 one-dollar bills, but how much will you need in coins if you want to have exact change ready?", "choices": {"A": "7\uffe0", "B": "8\uffe0", "C": "19\uffe0", "D": "27\uffe0", "E": "63\uffe0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. For which nonnegative value of x is the expression  undefined?", "choices": {"A": "81", "B": "18", "C": "9", "D": "3", "E": "0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the correct ordering of \u03c0, and 3 from least to greatest?", "choices": {"A": "3 &lt; \u03c0 &lt;", "B": "3 &lt; &lt; \u03c0", "C": "\u03c0 &lt; 3 &lt;", "D": "&lt; 3 &lt; \u03c0", "E": "&lt; \u03c0 &lt; 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Two strips of tape are to be used to wrap a box, as shown below. Both strips must go completely around the box. What is the minimum length of tape, in centimeters (cm), required to wrap the box?", "choices": {"A": "102", "B": "112", "C": "144", "D": "204", "E": "244"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. You have been asked to make punch for a wedding reception. The punch recipe calls for 6 parts fruit juices to 2 parts soda. To make 24 quarts of this punch, how many quarts of soda should you use?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "12", "E": "20"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Which of the following gives all the solutions of x2 - x = 12 ?", "choices": {"A": "-4 and 3", "B": "-3 and 4", "C": "-2 and 6", "D": "12 and 13", "E": "13 only"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. If (m - n)2 = 25 and mn = 36, then m2 + n2 = ?", "choices": {"A": "-47", "B": "-11", "C": "61", "D": "86", "E": "97"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. If, for all x, (x2a - 1)3 = x9, then a = ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. For the complex number i such that i2 = -1, what is the value of i4 + 2i2 ?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "-1", "C": "0", "D": "1", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. One endpoint of a line segment in the (x, y) coordinate plane has coordinates (5, -8). The midpoint of the segment has coordinates (-1, 4). What are the coordinates of the other endpoint of the segment?", "choices": {"A": " (-7, 16)", "B": "(-4, -32)", "C": "(2, -2)", "D": "(3, -6)", "E": "(4, 12)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In the (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the radius of the circle (x - 2)2 + (y + 1)2 = 6 ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "2", "D": "", "E": "6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In the right triangle pictured below, r, s, and t are the lengths of its sides. What is the value of cos \u03b2 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. For all nonzero a and b,= ?", "choices": {"A": "-15b", "B": "-15a2b", "C": "-15a2b2", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. In the figure below, 3 parallel lines are crossed by 2 transversals as shown. The points of intersection and some distances, in inches, are labeled. What is the length, in inches, of YX ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. The figure below shows square OABC and also shows the circle centered at O with radii OC and OA. If the area the square is 36 square units, what is the area of the circle, in square units?", "choices": {"A": "12\u03c0", "B": "18\u03c0", "C": "36\u03c0", "D": "72\u03c0", "E": "81\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Which of the following logical statements identifies the same set as the graph shown below?", "choices": {"A": "x \u2264 -4 or x &gt; 3", "B": "x &gt; -4 or x \u2264 3", "C": "x \u2265 -4 or x \uff1c 3", "D": "x \uff1e -4 and x \u2264 3", "E": "x \u2265 -4 and x \uff1c 3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. A forest begins 300 feet from the center of the base of a vertical television tower, across level ground. If the tower is 400 feet tall, how many feet is it.from the top of the tower to the nearest edge of the forest at ground level?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "500", "D": "700", "E": "120,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. If x and y are real and \uff1d 1, then what must be true of the value of y ?", "choices": {"A": "y must be positive", "B": "y must be negative", "C": "y must equal ", "D": "y must equal 2", "E": "y may have any value"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. If c is a positive integer that divides both 75 and 90, but divides neither 18 nor 10, what should you get when you add the digits in c ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. What is the slope of any line parallel to the x-axis in the (x, y) coordinate plane ?", "choices": {"A": "-1", "B": "0", "C": "1", "D": "Undefined", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Which of the following lines has the largest slope ?", "choices": {"A": "y = 3x - 1", "B": "y = 2x + 12", "C": "y = 4x + ", "D": "4y = 2x + 8", "E": "5y = 10x - 2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The 2 triangles in the figure below share a common side. What is sin (a + b) ?\n(Note: sin(a + b) = sin a cos b + sin b cos a for all a and b.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Rita can walk 2 miles in m minutes. At that pace, how many minutes would it take her to walk 7 miles?", "choices": {"A": "14m", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Which of the following calculations will yield an even integer for any integer n ?", "choices": {"A": "n2", "B": "3n2", "C": "4n2", "D": "3n2 + 1", "E": "4n2 + 1"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. In \u25b3ABC, the measure of \u2220A is 30\u00b0 and the measure of \u2220B is 60\u00b0 . If AB is 12 units long, what is the area, in square units, of \u25b3ABC ?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "", "C": "36", "D": "72", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Trapezoid ABCD below is isosceles, with side lengths as marked. Its diagonals intersect at E. What is the ratio of the length of AE to the length of DE \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "1", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A certain rectangle is 3 times as long as it is wide. Suppose the length and width are both doubled. The area of the second rectangle is how many times as large as the area of the first?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "12"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. For what value of a would the following system of equations have an infinite number of solutions?\n2x- 3y = 8\n6x- 9y = 4a", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "24", "E": "32"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Two ships leave a port at the same time. One ship moves at 20 miles per hour and sails 2 hours north, and then 1 hour east. The other ship moves at 25 miles per hour and sails 2 hours east, and then 1 hour north. Which of the following is an expression for the number of miles apart the ships are 3 hours after they leave port?", "choices": {"A": "3(25 - 20)", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. When measured from a point on the ground that is 40 meters from the base of an antenna, the angle of elevation to the top of the antenna is 42\u00b0, as shown below. What is the height, in meters, of the antenna ?", "choices": {"A": "40 cos 42\u00b0", "B": "40 cot 42\u00b0", "C": "40 sec 42\u00b0", "D": "40 sin 42\u00b0", "E": "40 tan 42\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. In the parallelogram below, lengths are given in centimeters. What is the area of the parallelogram, in square centimeters?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Points X, Y, and Z lie on the same line. If the length of XY is 5 meters and the length of YZ is 3 meters, then what are all the possible lengths, in meters, for XZ \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "2 only", "B": "8 only", "C": "2 and 8 only", "D": "Any number less than 2 or greater than 8", "E": "Any number greater than 2 and less than 8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Given the vertices of parallelogram ABCD in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below,what is the area of \u25b3ABC, in square units ?", "choices": {"A": "10.5", "B": "21.0", "C": "42.0", "D": "45.0", "E": "90.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. If 2a2b3 &lt; 0, then which of the following CANNOT be true?", "choices": {"A": " a = b", "B": "a \uff1c 0", "C": "a \uff1e 0", "D": "b \uff1c 0", "E": "b \uff1e 0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The first and second terms of a geometric sequence are n and an, in that order. What is the 1,000th term of the sequence?", "choices": {"A": "a999 n", "B": "a1,000 n", "C": "a1,001 n", "D": "(an)999", "E": "(an)1,000"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. If a system of 2 linear equations in 2 variables has NO solution, and 1 of the equations is graphed in the (x, y) coordinate plane below, which of the following could be the equation of the other line?", "choices": {"A": "y = -2x + 2", "B": "y = 2x + 2", "C": "y = -2x - 3", "D": "y = 2x + 3", "E": "y = 2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. If 0\u00b0 \u2264 x \u2264 90\u00b0 and sin x=, then tan x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. For every cent decrease in price of a gallon of gasoline, a station sells 250 more gallons per day. The station normally sells 3,000 gallons of gasoline a day at $1.09 per gallon. Which of the following expressions represents the number of gallons of gasoline sold per day if the cost is reduced by x cents per gallon?", "choices": {"A": "3,000(1.09 - x)", "B": "1.09(250x + 3,000)", "C": "(1.09 - x)(250x + 3,000)", "D": "1.09 - x", "E": "3,000 + 250x"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. In a game, 100 marbles numbered 00 through 99 are placed in a box. A player draws 1 marble at random from the box. Without replacing the first marble, the player draws a second marble at random. If both marbles drawn have the same tens digit (that is, both are numbered between 00 and 09, or 10 and 19, or 20 and 29 etc.), the player is a winner. If the first marble Terry draws is numbered 87, what is the probability that Terry will be a winner on the next draw?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The figure below shows a cross section of a swimming pool that is 50 feet (ft) wide and 75 ft long. The bottom is horizontal for 25 ft, then slopes up, snd the sides are vertical. What is the volume of water, in cubic ft, that is required to fill the pool to a depth, as shown, of 10 ft at the deep end and 4 ft at the shallow end ?", "choices": {"A": "600", "B": "25,000", "C": "26,250", "D": "30,000", "E": "47,500"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  In the figure below, line l has the equation y = x. Line k is above l, as shown, and k is parallel to l. Which of the following is an equation for k ?", "choices": {"A": "y = x + 2", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "y = 2x", "E": "y = 2x + 2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. What is the smallest possible value for the product of 2 real numbers that differ by 6 ?", "choices": {"A": "-36", "B": "-9", "C": "-6", "D": "0", "E": "9"}, "correct": "B"}]}